## **CHENG HUAN AN**

huanchen@visa.com • +65 9772 1466 • Singapore • linkedin.com/in/huan-an-cheng

## **SUMMARY**

Responsible and reliable individual who is able to complete tasks independently as well as in teams. Has experience in multiple fields, but mainly dealt with automation and backend development with a preference for Python as the programming language.

#### **EDUCATION**

## SINGAPORE UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY AND DESIGN

May 2017 - Sep 2020

## Bachelors in Engineering, Information Systems Technology and Design (Honours with Distinction)

• Scholarship recipient of the Ngee Ann Kongsi - SUTD Scholarship for outstanding Singapore-Cambridge GCE 'A' level results and active involvement in co-curricular activities and community projects

## NATIONAL TAIWAN UNIVERSITY

#### Computer Science and Information Engineering

Sep 2019 - Jan 2021

 Awarded the Temasek Foundation International Leadership Enrichment and Regional Networking Programme scholarship which was only given to 4 SUTD students in 2019

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### VISA INC.

## Software Engineer (Production/Support Role)

Oct 2021 - Present

- Automated several recurring manual processes using shell scripts and Python, reducing a few hours of work to minutes
- Wrote over 10 documentations detailing steps required for various production support activities in the team
- Maintain security of servers and assist with production support both independently and alongside various teams to diagnose and resolve problems (pager duty to begin from mid-March 2021)

## Software Engineer Intern

May 2019 – Aug 2019

• Developed an interface that allows for the automated execution of the switching of data centers for a major application within the team, along with the display of its execution status. Front-end: Angular, Backend: Java, Spring

## **BO CONG ANH STUDIO – VIETNAM**

## Quality Assurance Intern

May 2018- Aug 2018

- Performed black-box UI and functional testing at different phases of development of a website and two mobile applications
- Initiated and introduced the use of automated testing using Selenium, Appium and Applitools Eyes
- Delegated tasks on behalf of the project manager using Trello and worked alongside developers in solving bugs and discrepancies in designs
- Attended meetings with clients and addressed their questions and requests for new features on a regular basis

## **PROJECTS**

## AUTOMATED THREAT MODELLING IN DEVSECOPS

## Capstone Project with DBS

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

- Worked in a multi-disciplinary team of 7 and our industry mentor in going through the design process of problem statement scoping, analysis of current market solutions, ideation and iterations before coming up with an intuitive, actionable tool that is able to present security threats and mitigations based on the components of a software project
- Developed the backend code for the generation of 'attack trees' representations of possible security threats and mitigations by extracting relevant data from multiple threat libraries according to given inputs using Python with Selenium, Pandas and various other libraries
- Used cronjob for scheduling updates and Git for version control
- Contributed to presentations, reports, technical documentations etc.
- Public-facing video demo: <a href="https://youtu.be/T8Hg9cVfqzc">https://youtu.be/T8Hg9cVfqzc</a>

# **DECENTRALISED APPLICATION - CHARITRUST**

## Individual School Project

Apr 2020

 ChariTrust is a prototype blockchain fundraising platform aimed to increase transparency and accountability in how donations are being handled

- Prepared the idea and presentation and coded the smart contracts, front-end and back-end of the project using Solidity, Ganache, Metamask, Flask and HTML/CSS/JS in a tight deadline of 3 days
- Video presentation: https://youtu.be/zU1BJmM5h1g

#### **BLOCKCHAIN PROJECT - SUTDcoin**

Group School Project Mar 2020

• Worked in a team of 4 to simulate a blockchain in Python demonstrating the following activities: validation of transactions, ledger system, double-spending attack and selfish-mining

#### **EVENT SCHEDULING WEBSITE**

## **Group School Project**

Feb 2019 - May 2019

- Worked in a team of 4 to create a website for event scheduling
- Designed use cases and class diagrams
- Implemented the front-end of the website using Bootstrap atop HTML/CSS/JS and handled the backend implementations using Django and SQLite

## **ORGANIZATIONS**

#### SUTD CENTRE FOR WRITING AND RHETORIC

## Undergraduate Writing Advisor

Nov 2017 - Sep 2020

Appointed to be one of approximately 10 students whom fellow undergraduates can contact for writing help or essay reviews

## SUTD PRODUCTIONS

**Education Manager** 

Aug 2017 – Nov 2018

- Created educational materials and organised over 10 workshops to educate students on the different aspects of a film, such as camera operations, video editing, styles of films, sound design and so on
- Part of the 2018 Exco given the Outstanding Student Organisation award in the university
- Involved in multiple video productions, taking on different roles including script-writing, producing, filming and editing

## SUTD UNIVERSITY AMBASSADORS

Member

Sep 2017 – Sep 2019

 Led campus tours for over hundreds of guests and prospective students and addressed queries about the school in acceptance teas, donor appreciations and various other external-facing events

# SUTD DIGITAL AND DEVELOPMENT CLUB

## Club Representative for Women In Tech Event

Jun 2017 – Aug 2017

- Taught the basics of coding using Sphero to interested visitors of the event
- Liaised with the university's marketing department to handle the admin and logistics of the event for the club's booth
- Led a team of 7 members in the preparation for the event

## SKILLS, ACTIVITIES & INTEREST

- Programming Languages: Python (preferred), Bash, Java, Go, C#, Typescript, Javascript, HTML/CSS (markup)
- *Skills:* Automation (Shell Scripting/Python), Software Development, Web Development, Version Control (Git), Mockups (Adobe XD), Content Creation (Adobe Premiere Pro, Audition, Photoshop), Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)
- Language: Fluent in spoken and written English and Mandarin
- Interests. Piano (Completed Grade 8 ABRSM Practical Exam), shows, board games and reading